<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?> <!-- file updated 3/26 --> <!-- NOTE:  		any formating (spaces, returns, tabs) inside a tag will show up in the flash display of text 		grouped items off the root will be stored in objects named by tag in flash 		attributes in the root tag will be variables on the root 		attributes of groups off the root will be stored as global variables 	the text that needs to be linked are set apart in seperate tags- even if part of sentence so that they can be formated correctly		inside whatever text grouping they belong-   --><root sectiontitle= "Sorting People" timelapse = "3"> 	<activity id="1"> 		<item> 		<!-- screen001 --> 		<subtitle>Who Goes Where?</subtitle>				<tagline>See if you can guess how each of these people would be identified based on current U.S. racial categories.</tagline>		<taglinelink>current U.S. racial categories</taglinelink>		<instructions> Drag each photo to a box under the appropriate classification. Click on a photo to see an enlargement.</instructions>		<popup>The U.S. federal government currently recognizes six major racial and ethnic categories:(1) American Indian or Alaska Native; (2) Asian; (3) Black or African American; (4) Hispanic or Latino; (5) White; (6) Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander.Based on our pool of participants, we omitted the last category for this activity.In recent years, people have been allowed to check more than one race. However, the government still requires that multiple responses be collapsed for reporting - following suit, we have "assigned" our participants to one category each.</popup>		</item>		<item>		<!-- screen002 -->			<subtitle>Did You Know?</subtitle>			<header>Something to think about...</header>			<bodytext>Until 1960, census enumerators classified people into races the same way you just did - by looking at them.In 1970, after many civil rights laws were passed, U.S. citizens were able to choose their own classification. This is known as "self-identification."</bodytext>			<italictext>enumerators</italictext>		</item>		<item>		<!-- screen003 -->			<subtitle>How Well Did You Do?</subtitle>			<tagline>Compare your guess with the U.S. Race classifications below. Faded images indicate incorrect matches.</tagline>			<instructions>Click on a photo to learn more about each person and see how they think of themselves.</instructions>		</item>		<item>		<!-- screen004 -->			<subtitle>Conclusion</subtitle>			<header>Classifying people is a highly subjective process.</header>			<!-- copy is split into 3 formats - will have to  format based on linebreaks -->			<bodytext>As you can see, appearance doesn't always tell you about someone's ancestry or self-identity. It's hard to make any accurate predictions based on appearance alone.</bodytext><bodytext1>Racial categories in the U.S. have changed over time. Also, other countries define race differently.</bodytext1><bodytext2>Classifying people isn't necessarily good or bad. It depends on the purpose. "Race" can't tell you where somebody is from, what they're naturally good at, or how they might behave. But it can tell you who is being discriminated against and who lacks certain opportunities.</bodytext2><bodytext3>Explore other traits to see different ways to sort people or see the "Go Deeper" section to learn more about racial classification.</bodytext3>		</item> 	</activity> 		<assets>		<arrays>			<!-- 							     0			1	  2		3				4		-->			<item name="categories_array">AmericanIndian,Asian,Black,Hispanic/Latino,White</item>		</arrays>	</assets></root>